class QuestionModel{
  final String question;
  final List<String> options;
  final correctAnswerIndex;
  final String Solution;

  const QuestionModel({
    required this.question,
    required this.options,
    required this.correctAnswerIndex,
    required this.Solution,
  });
}
List<QuestionModel> remote_sencing_in_agriculture = [


  QuestionModel(question: "1. What is the primary purpose of using remote sensing in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Entertainment",
        "B. Crop monitoring",
        "C. Weather forecasting",
        "D. Space exploration",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Remote sensing in agriculture is primarily used for crop monitoring. It helps in assessing crop health, identifying diseases, and optimizing agricultural practices.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "2. Which type of remote sensing technology is commonly used to gather information about crop health?",
      options: [
        "A. Radar",
        "B. LiDAR",
        "C. Infrared imaging",
        "D. X-ray imaging",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Infrared imaging is commonly used in remote sensing for agriculture to assess crop health. It can highlight variations in plant health that are not visible to the naked eye.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "3. How can remote sensing assist in precision agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. By randomly scattering seeds",
        "B. By providing precise information about crop conditions",
        "C. By using outdated satellite images",
        "D. By ignoring weather patterns",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Remote sensing helps in precision agriculture by providing precise information about crop conditions. This allows farmers to make data-driven decisions for optimized crop management.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "4. What is NDVI (Normalized Difference Vegetation Index) used for in remote sensing?",
      options: [
        "A. Measuring soil moisture",
        "B. Assessing crop health",
        "C. Counting the number of leaves on a plant",
        "D. Calculating rainfall",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'NDVI is used in remote sensing to assess crop health. It measures the difference between near-infrared and red light reflected by vegetation, providing insights into plant health.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "5. Which satellite sensor is commonly used for monitoring agricultural land at a global scale?",
      options: [
        "A. Hubble Space Telescope",
        "B. Landsat",
        "C. GPS satellite",
        "D. International Space Station",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Landsat is a commonly used satellite sensor for monitoring agricultural land at a global scale. It provides high-resolution images that aid in various agricultural applications.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "6. How does LiDAR technology contribute to agricultural mapping?",
      options: [
        "A. By capturing detailed 3D topographic information",
        "B. By measuring radio waves",
        "C. By analyzing soil composition",
        "D. By detecting ultraviolet light",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: 'LiDAR contributes to agricultural mapping by capturing detailed 3D topographic information. This information is valuable for terrain analysis and precise agricultural planning.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "7. In precision agriculture, what is the purpose of variable rate technology (VRT)?",
      options: [
        "A. Consistent application of resources",
        "B. Random distribution of seeds",
        "C. Ignoring soil variations",
        "D. Manual irrigation",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 0,
      Solution: 'Variable rate technology (VRT) in precision agriculture aims for consistent application of resources, adjusting inputs based on the specific needs of different areas within a field.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "8. How can remote sensing contribute to early detection of crop diseases?",
      options: [
        "A. By counting the number of birds in the area",
        "B. By monitoring temperature changes",
        "C. By analyzing spectral signatures",
        "D. By observing cloud formations",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Remote sensing contributes to early detection of crop diseases by analyzing spectral signatures. Changes in plant reflectance can indicate the presence of diseases before visible symptoms appear.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "9. What is the role of GIS (Geographic Information System) in conjunction with remote sensing in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Generating musical compositions",
        "B. Analyzing spatial data for better decision-making",
        "C. Predicting the stock market",
        "D. Designing fashion accessories",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'GIS, in conjunction with remote sensing, plays a crucial role in analyzing spatial data for better decision-making in agriculture. It helps integrate and interpret diverse information for effective planning.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "10. How do drones contribute to remote sensing in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. By delivering groceries",
        "B. By capturing high-resolution images and data",
        "C. By predicting earthquakes",
        "D. By providing internet connectivity",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Drones contribute to remote sensing in agriculture by capturing high-resolution images and data. They offer a cost-effective and efficient way to monitor crops and assess field conditions.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "11. Which of the following is a benefit of using remote sensing for irrigation management?",
      options: [
        "A. Overwatering crops",
        "B. Underwatering crops",
        "C. Optimal water usage",
        "D. Ignoring water requirements",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'A benefit of using remote sensing for irrigation management is optimal water usage. It allows farmers to monitor soil moisture levels and apply water precisely where and when needed.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "12. What does the term 'spectral resolution' refer to in remote sensing?",
      options: [
        "A. The clarity of images captured",
        "B. The range of wavelengths recorded by a sensor",
        "C. The speed of data transmission",
        "D. The height of satellites above Earth",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Spectral resolution in remote sensing refers to the range of wavelengths recorded by a sensor. It determines the level of detail in the spectral information captured from the Earth’s surface.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "13. How can remote sensing technologies help in monitoring soil conditions?",
      options: [
        "A. By tasting the soil",
        "B. By measuring soil temperature",
        "C. By analyzing satellite images",
        "D. By listening to the soil",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Remote sensing technologies help in monitoring soil conditions by analyzing satellite images. They provide valuable information about soil composition, moisture levels, and nutrient content.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "14. What is the significance of temporal resolution in remote sensing?",
      options: [
        "A. The number of pixels in an image",
        "B. The frequency of image acquisition over time",
        "C. The clarity of images",
        "D. The speed of data processing",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Temporal resolution in remote sensing refers to the frequency of image acquisition over time. It is crucial for monitoring changes on the Earth’s surface, such as seasonal variations in vegetation.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "15. How does remote sensing contribute to yield prediction in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. By predicting the stock market",
        "B. By counting the number of birds in the area",
        "C. By analyzing crop health and environmental factors",
        "D. By measuring wind speed",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Remote sensing contributes to yield prediction in agriculture by analyzing crop health and environmental factors. This information helps estimate potential crop yields and plan harvesting accordingly.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "16. What is the primary advantage of using satellite-based remote sensing in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. Limited coverage",
        "B. Real-time data acquisition",
        "C. High operational cost",
        "D. Low spatial resolution",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'The primary advantage of using satellite-based remote sensing in agriculture is real-time data acquisition. Satellites provide timely and up-to-date information for effective decision-making.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "17. In precision agriculture, what role does GPS play in conjunction with remote sensing?",
      options: [
        "A. Guiding tractors for random movement",
        "B. Providing accurate location information",
        "C. Ignoring spatial variability",
        "D. Monitoring air pollution",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'In precision agriculture, GPS plays a crucial role in conjunction with remote sensing by providing accurate location information. This helps in precisely navigating farming equipment and mapping field variations.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "18. How can remote sensing contribute to crop insurance assessments?",
      options: [
        "A. By predicting the stock market",
        "B. By analyzing spectral signatures of crops",
        "C. By counting the number of birds in the area",
        "D. By measuring ocean temperatures",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 1,
      Solution: 'Remote sensing contributes to crop insurance assessments by analyzing spectral signatures of crops. It provides valuable information for assessing crop health and potential risks.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "19. What is the primary advantage of using UAVs (Unmanned Aerial Vehicles) for agricultural remote sensing?",
      options: [
        "A. Limited mobility",
        "B. High operational cost",
        "C. Low spatial resolution",
        "D. Flexibility and accessibility",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 3,
      Solution: 'The primary advantage of using UAVs for agricultural remote sensing is flexibility and accessibility. UAVs can be deployed easily to capture high-resolution images and data over specific areas.'
  ),

  QuestionModel(question: "20. How does remote sensing contribute to land-use planning in agriculture?",
      options: [
        "A. By randomly selecting land-use patterns",
        "B. By ignoring soil variations",
        "C. By analyzing satellite images for informed decision-making",
        "D. By relying on outdated maps",
      ],
      correctAnswerIndex: 2,
      Solution: 'Remote sensing contributes to land-use planning in agriculture by analyzing satellite images for informed decision-making. It helps in identifying suitable areas for different crops and optimizing land utilization.'
  ),

  ];